export const CHEMISTRYA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following species determines the chemical properties of an atom?",
A: "Electron",
B: "Neutron",
C: "Nucleus",
D: "Proton",
answer: "A. Electron",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The following glasswares are used to measure the volume of liquids EXCEPT",
A: "graduated beaker",
B: "pipette",
C: "test tube",
D: "burette",
answer: "C. test tube",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Pauli exclusion principle is related to",
A: "quantity of electrons in the valence shell",
B: "filling the orbitals with lower energy first",
C: "the filling of degenerated orbitals",
D: "quantum numbers of electrons",
answer: "D. quantum numbers of electrons",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The species with no electron in the 3d-orbital is",
A: "Zn2+",
B: "Sc3+",
C: "Cu",
D: "Mn",
answer: "B. Sc3+",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The separation of Nitrogen from oxygen using fractional distillation of air is possible because",
A: "nitrogen is less dense than oxygen",
B: "oxygen is more reactive than nitrogen",
C: "of the difference in their boiling points",
D: "they belong to the same period",
answer: "C. of the difference in their boiling points",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The purity of a solid sample can best be determined by its",
A: "boiling point",
B: "melting point",
C: "conductivity",
D: "solubility",
answer: "B. melting point",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The mass of one mole of (NH4)2CO3 is   [O=16.0, N=14.0, C=12.0, H=1.0]",
A: "66.0g",
B: "76.0g",
C: "80.0g",
D: "96.0g",
answer: "D. 96.0g",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Atomic orbital is",
A: "the circular path through which electrons revolve round the nucleus",
B: "a region around the nucleus where electrons are most likely to be found",
C: "the path around the nucleus through which electrons move",
D: "the path around the nucleus through which protons move",
answer: "B. a region around the nucleus where electrons are most likely to be found",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The property of elements which increases down a group of the periodic table is",
A: "electronegativity",
B: "electron affinity",
C: "ionic radius",
D: "ionization energy",
answer: "C. ionic radius",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The reason for the decrease in the atomic size of elements across a period is that",
A: "nuclear charge increases while the outermost electrons are drawn closer to the nucleus",
B: "nuclear charge decreases while the outermost electrons are drawn closer to the nucleus",
C: "valence electrons increase across the period while the valence shell remains constant",
D: "nuclear charge decreases while the distance of the valence shell from the nucleus is increasing",
answer: "A. nuclear charge increases while the outermost electrons are drawn closer to the nucleus",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The oxidation number of nitrogen in Pb(NO3)2 is",
A: "+2",
B: "+3",
C: "+4",
D: "+5",
answer: "D. +5",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following arrangements indicates the correct decreasing order of ionization energy of period 3 elements?",
A: "Na, Al, P, Cl",
B: "Cl, P, Al, Na",
C: "Na, P, Cl, Al",
D: "Al, Na, P, Cl",
answer: "B. Cl, P, Al, Na",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following metals has the strongest metallic bond?",
A: "13Al",
B: "19K",
C: "12Mg",
D: "11Na",
answer: "A. 13Al",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following substances does not have van der Waals' forces?",
A: "Copper",
B: "Graphite",
C: "Neon",
D: "Iodine crystals",
answer: "A. Copper",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The oxidation number of X in XO3+4.  is",
A: "+1",
B: "+3",
C: "+4",
D: "+5",
answer: "D. +5",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The ionization energy is affected by the following factors except",
A: "distance of the outermost electron(s) from the nucleus",
B: "size of the positive nuclear charge",
C: "ability to attract shared electron(s)",
D: "screening effect of the inner electron(s)",
answer: "C. ability to attract shared electron(s)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following statements is correct?",
A: "Covalent compounds would readily ionize in solution",
B: "Covalent compounds consist of ions",
C: "Hydrogen bond is formed between a metal and a non-metal",
D: "Ionic compounds in solution would conduct electricity",
answer: "D. Ionic compounds in solution would conduct electricity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The bond angle in tetrahedral molecules such as tetrachloromethane is",
A: "180.0°",
B: "109.5°",
C: "105.5°",
D: "90.0°",
answer: "B. 109.5°",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The properties of a good primary standard include the following except",
A: "high molecular mass",
B: "low molecular mass",
C: "high degree of purity",
D: "readily available",
answer: "B. low molecular mass",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The use of diamond in abrasives is due to its",
A: "high melting point",
B: "hardness",
C: "octahedral shape",
D: "durability",
answer: "B. hardness",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following statements about endothermic reaction is correct?",
A: "Activation energy is high",
B: "A catalyst is required",
C: "It occurs reversibly",
D: "Heat energy is absorbed",
answer: "D. Heat energy is absorbed",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A 0.1moldm−3 solution of sodium hydroxide was diluted with distilled water to 0.001moldm−3. What is the dilution factor?",
A: "1000.00",
B: "100.00",
C: "10.00",
D: "0.01",
answer: "D. 0.01",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Graphite and Diamond are similar in that they",
A: "have octahedral shape",
B: "have same density",
C: "form carbon(IV) oxide on combustion",
D: "conduct electricity",
answer: "C. form carbon(IV) oxide on combustion",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. In a saturated solution at a given temperature, the undissolved solutes are in equilibrium with",
A: "the solvent",
B: "dissolved solute particles",
C: "the saturated solution",
D: "insoluble solute particles",
answer: "C. the saturated solution",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The number of atoms present in 2.5moles of a triatomic gas is equivalent to    [1mole = 6.02×1023]",
A: "2.5×1023",
B: "1.5×1023",
C: "1.5×1024",
D: "2.5×1024",
answer: "C. 1.5×1024",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. When Magnesium reacts with oxygen, heat is",
A: "absorbed and the reaction is endothermic",
B: "evolved and the reaction is endothermic",
C: "evolved and the reaction is exothermic",
D: "absorbed and the reaction is exothermic",
answer: "C. evolved and the reaction is exothermic",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following gases is not acidic?",
A: "SO3",
B: "NO2",
C: "Co2",
D: "CO",
answer: "D. CO",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A hydrocarbon contained 14.3% hydrogen. The empirical formula for the hydrocarbon is    [H= 1.0, C= 12.0]",
A: "CH",
B: "CH2",
C: "CH3",
D: "CH4",
answer: "B. CH2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following statements is NOT a chemical property of an acid?",
A: "Evolution of ammonia when heated with ammonium salts",
B: "Evolution of carbon dioxide gas when added to a trioxocarbonate (IV) salt",
C: "Formation of salt and water with alkalis",
D: "Formation of salt and hydrogen gas with reactive metals",
answer: "A. Evolution of ammonia when heated with ammonium salts",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Halogens generally react with metals to form",
A: "alkalis",
B: "acids",
C: "bases",
D: "salts",
answer: "D. salts",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Potassium Chloride solid does not conduct electricity because",
A: "it is a covalent compound",
B: "strong cohesive forces make its ions immobile",
C: "strong cohesive force makes its molecule immobile",
D: "each of potassium and chlorine structures contain noble gas structure",
answer: "B. strong cohesive forces make its ions immobile",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. When water was added to a white anhydrous substance X, the colour changed to blue. X is",
A: "CuSO4",
B: "FeSO4",
C: "Na2SO4",
D: "PbSO4",
answer: "A. CuSO4",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Solubility curve can be used in the determination of the",
A: "amount of crystals formed",
B: "amount of solvent that can be recovered",
C: "amount of solid drugs in a given solution",
D: "temperature of the solution",
answer: "C. amount of solid drugs in a given solution",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. If 0.2g of a salt is required to saturate 200cm3 of water at room temperature, what is the solubility of the salt?",
A: "0.2gdm−3",
B: "1.0gdm−3",
C: "2.0gdm−3",
D: "5.0gdm−3",
answer: "B. 1.0gdm−3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The property of a chemical reaction that is affected by the presence of a catalyst is",
A: "activation energy",
B: "free energy",
C: "equilibrium position",
D: "enthalpy change",
answer: "A. activation energy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Soluble salts can be prepared by the following methods except",
A: "neutralization",
B: "reaction of an acid with trioxocarbonate(IV) salt",
C: "double decomposition",
D: "reaction of an acid with electropositive metals",
answer: "C. double decomposition",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Chemical reactions occurs when the colliding reactants have energy that is",
A: "less than the activation energy",
B: "greater than the activation energy",
C: "greater than the energy of the product",
D: "less than the energy of effective collision",
answer: "B. greater than the activation energy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The common feature of reactions at the anode is that",
A: "electrons are consumed",
B: "ions are reduced",
C: "oxidation is involved",
D: "the electrode dissolves",
answer: "C. oxidation is involved",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Consider the following reaction equation: 2NO(g)+O2(g)→2NO2(g). What is the change in the oxidation number of nitrogen?",
A: "+2 to 0",
B: "+2 to -2",
C: "+2 to +4",
D: "+4 to +2",
answer: "C. +2 to +4",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following factors characterize members of the same homologous series?",
A: "The chemical property change gradually throughout the series",
B: "physical properties of members are similar",
C: "They have the same molecular formular",
D: "Successive members undergo changes in molecular formula by CH2",
answer: "D. Successive members undergo changes in molecular formula by CH2",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Calculate the mass of copper deposited if a current of 0.45A flows through CuSO4 solution for 1hour 15mins.   [Cu=64.0, S= 32.0, O =16.0, 1F= 96500C]",
A: "6.40g",
B: "0.67g",
C: "0.64g",
D: "0.45g",
answer: "B. 0.67g",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Classification of alkanols is based on the",
A: "number of carbon atoms present in the compound",
B: "molecular mass of the compound",
C: "molecular formula of the compound",
D: "number of alkyl groups bonded to the carbon having the hydroxyl group",
answer: "D. number of alkyl groups bonded to the carbon having the hydroxyl group",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The name of the compound C4H9COOC3H7 is",
A: "propyl pentanoate",
B: "pentyl propanoate",
C: "butyl propanoate",
D: "propyl butanoate",
answer: "A. propyl pentanoate",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following pairs of gases are pollutants from car exhaust?",
A: "Nitrogen(II) oxide and Carbon(IV) oxide",
B: "Carbon(IV) oxide and Nitrogen",
C: "Carbon(II) oxide and Sulphur(IV) oxide",
D: "Carbon(II) oxide and oxygen",
answer: "C. Carbon(II) oxide and Sulphur(IV) oxide",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Fats and oils can be obtained from any of the following sources except",
A: "paraffin oil",
B: "animals",
C: "groundnuts",
D: "palm kernel",
answer: "A. paraffin oil",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The condensation of two units of glucose will produce a disaccharide with the formula C12H22O11 which is",
A: "sucrose",
B: "maltose",
C: "galactose",
D: "mannose",
answer: "B. maltose",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The IUPAC name for the compound ClCH2CH2OH is",
A: "1- chloropropanol",
B: "2-chloropropanol",
C: "1-chloroethanol",
D: "2-chloroethanol",
answer: "C. 1-chloroethanol",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The real harmful effect of the release of chlorofluorocarbons into the atmosphere is that it eventually causes",
A: "excessive ultraviolet light from the sun to reach the earth surface",
B: "excessive release of infrared light from the sun to the earth surface",
C: "corrosive effect of the chemicals on humans and animals",
D: "acidic effect of chemicals on humans",
answer: "A. excessive ultraviolet light from the sun to reach the earth surface",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. A primary alkanol has a molecular mass of 60. What is the structural formula of the compound? [C= 12.0, H= 1.0, O= 16.0)",
A: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
B: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
C: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
D: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
answer: "B. zzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Petroleum is a non-renewable source of energy because it",
A: "is formed naturally",
B: "is cheap",
C: "can be recycled after use",
D: "cannot be regenerated once used up",
answer: "D. cannot be regenerated once used up",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]